Guide to the New England Grenfell Association Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
New England Grenfell Association records
1912-1978
MS 1200
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
11
The records include correspondence, minutes of meetings, office files, financial and legal papers, and memorabilia of the New England Grenfell Association, founded in 1914 to promote missionary and medical work in Labrador and Newfoundland.
New England Grenfell Association
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of New England Grenfell Association, 1980.
Scope and Contents
The New England Grenfell Association was founded in 1914 in order to promote missionary and medical work in Labrador and Newfoundland, Canada.
The records include correspondence, minutes of meetings, office files, financial and legal papers, and memorabilia of the New England Grenfell Association. The records date from 1912 to 1978 and are arranged in fifteen boxes which total ten linear feet. The New England Grenfell Association donated the records in 1980.
The records are arranged in two series:
SERIES I consists of routine office correspondence, memoranda, and files relating to the daily operations of the association. The bulk of material concerns the financial operations of the organization including bequests, gifts, leases, and payrolls. Minutes of meetings of the Board of Directors are organized in folders 52-54 and these materials provide a detailed review of the activities and interests of the New England Grenfell Association.
SERIES II contains bound volumes of cash books, journals, and ledgers which provide detailed financial records for the transactions of the association.
Arrangement
Arranged in two series: I. Office Files. II. Financial Volumes.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Medicine; Missions -- Newfoundland and Labrador; Labrador (N.L.); Newfoundland and Labrador; New England Grenfell Association
- Office Files, Series I
  - Alumni reunion dinners, 1962-1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bequests
    - A, 1923-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - B, 1923-1972 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
    - C, 1923-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
    - D - E, 1923-1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - F, 1923-1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - G, 1923-1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - H, 1923-1972 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
    - J - L, 1923-1972 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - M - O, 1923-1972 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - P - R, 1923-1972 (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
    - S, 1923-1972 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - T, 1923-1972 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - U - W, 1923-1972 (Box 2, Folder 19-20)
  - Boston office closing, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Cash receipts, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Cash disbursements, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1946-1974 (Box 3, Folder 24-33)
    - Miscellaneous, 1971-1974 (Box 3, Folder 34-35)
  - Financial statements, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Gifts
    - General: A - Z, 1915-1970 (Box 4, Folder 37-38)
    - Restricted, 1916-1955 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Grenfell Labrador Medical Mission, Inc., 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Invested Funds General Ledger
    - C.I.F., 1941-1970 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Endowment: Williams, 1961-1970 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Endowment Funds Account, 1970-1973 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - New England Council, 1954-1970 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Williams Combined Industrial Funds, 1970-1973 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Lease 581 Boylston, MA, 02116 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Magazine subscriptions, 1973-1977 (Box 5, Folder 47-50)
  - Memorabilia, 1912-1977 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Minutes, 1914-1945, 1970-1972 (Box 5, Folder 52-54)
  - Payroll, 1950-1972 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Quebec-Labrador Mission Foundation, 1970-1975 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Remittances to I.G.A., 1975-1978 (Box 6, Folder 57-58)
  - Special projects, loans, quotas, etc., 1962-1974 (Box 6, Folder 59-64)
  - Miscellanea, 1965-1972 (Box 6, Folder 65)
- Financial Volumes, Series II
  - Cash books
    General
    See also: box 15, folder 95-96
    See also: box 14, folder 92-94
    See also: box 13, folder 90-91
    See also: box 12, folder 88-89
    - General, 1915-1925 (Box 7, Folder 66-67)
    - Combined Industrial funds, 1951-1964 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - Endowment funds, 1950-1972 (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - New England funds, 1950-1970 (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - Operating accounts, 1950-1964 (Box 8, Folder 71-73)
    - Williams fund, 1950-1969 (Box 8, Folder 74)
  - Journals
    - General, 1968-1973 (Box 9, Folder 75-76)
    - Investment fund, 1950-1968 (Box 9, Folder 77)
  - Ledgers, 1915-1923 (Box 9, Folder 78-79)
  - Ledgers, 1924-1942 (Box 10, Folder 80-83)
  - Ledgers (Box 11, Folder 84-87)
  - Cash books
    - No. 1-2, 1926-1931 (Box 12, Folder 88-89)
    - No. 3-4, 1932-1942 (Box 13, Folder 90-91)
    - No. 5-7, 1943-1965 (Box 14, Folder 92-94)
  - Ledgers, 1964-1973 (Box 15, Folder 95-96)
  - Audit of treasurer's accounts
    - 1922-1925 (Box 16, Folder 97)
    - 1927-1930 (Box 16, Folder 98)
    - 1931-1935 (Box 16, Folder 99)
    - 1936-1940 (Box 16, Folder 100)
    - 1941-1945 (Box 16, Folder 101)
    - 1946-1950 May (Box 17, Folder 102)
    - 1950 June-1955 March (Box 17, Folder 103)
    - 1956 April-1959 March (Box 17, Folder 104)
    - 1959 April-1962 Mar (Box 17, Folder 105)
    - 1962 April-1964 March (Box 17, Folder 106)
    - 1964 April-1969 March (Box 18, Folder 107)
    - 1969 April-1971 March (Box 18, Folder 108)
  - Endowment/New England Fund [principal and income], 1973 April-December (Box 18, Folder 109)
  - Endowment/New England Fund [accounts for 1976 through Mar] (Box 18, Folder 110)
  - Financial statements, schedules, and supplementary data [with accountants' report thereon], 1972-1980 (Box 18, Folder 111-112)
  - Invested funds [final balance], 1950 May (Box 18, Folder 113)
  - Quarterly reports and correspondence, 1964-1971 (Box 18, Folder 114)
  - Treasurer's reports (Box 18, Folder 114)
    - 1941-1957 (Box 18, Folder 115)
    - 1958-1978 (Box 18, Folder 116)
  - Williams Fund [principal and income], 1973 April-June (Box 18, Folder 117)